<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2024s on 20th Workshop on Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing</title><link>https://vhpc.github.io/2024/</link><description>Recent content in 2024s on 20th Workshop on Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vhpc.github.io/2024/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/2024/home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/2024/home/</guid><description>VHPC 2024 - 19th Workshop on Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing The 19th Workshop on Virtualization in High­-Performance Cloud Computing (VHPC 2024) aims to bring together researchers and industrial practitioners facing the challenges posed by virtualization in HPC/Cloud scenarios in order to foster discussion, collaboration, mutual exchange of knowledge and experience, enabling research to ultimately provide novel solutions for virtualized computing systems of tomorrow.
The workshop will be held in conjunction with the International European Conference on Parallel and Distributed Computing (Euro-Par 2024), on Aug 27th, 2024, in Madrid, Spain.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/2024/program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/2024/program/</guid><description>VHPC 2024 Program Keynote: Towards Using Partitioned GPU Virtual Functions for Mixture of Experts Vignesh Chander, Member of Technical Staff, AMD
This talk provides an in-depth overview of the ROCm software ecosystem on MI300X platforms, with a focus on large-scale training and inference of Large Language Models. It will also introduce some new use cases that leverage the new Spatial Partitioning modes and Virtualization capabilities to accelerate these workloads. Additionally, we will discuss some of the challenges and tools available for profiling, tuning, and debugging these complex systems, empowering developers to optimize their workloads and unlock the full potential of MI300X.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/2024/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/2024/schedule/</guid><description>VHPC 2024 Schedule Notes pad: https://pad.nbfc.io/p/vhpc2024
For detailed information on the contributions, including full authorship, please, refer to the program page.
13:25-13:30 Welcome Message from the VHPC&amp;rsquo;24 Chairs
13:30-14:25 Keynote Talk &amp;amp; Paper Presentation (session chair: Tommaso Cucinotta)
13:30-14:25 Towards Using Partitioned GPU Virtual Functions for Mixture of Experts. Vignesh Chander (Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.) 14:25-15:00 Session 1 (session chair: Luca Abeni)</description></item></channel></rss>