<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>20th Workshop on Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing</title><link>https://vhpc.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on 20th Workshop on Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vhpc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/2022/program-details/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/2022/program-details/</guid><description>VHPC 2022 Program Details Keynote Talks rtla: finding the sources of OS noise on Linux Speaker: Daniel Bristot De Oliveira, Senior Principal Software Engineer in the real-time kernel team at Red Hat.
Abstract: Currently, Real-time Linux is evaluated using a black-box approach. While this method provides an overview of the system, it fails to provide a root cause analysis for unexpected values. Developers have to use kernel trace features to debug these cases, requiring extensive knowledge about the system and fastidious tracing setup and breakdown.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/2023/keynote1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/2023/keynote1/</guid><description>Keynote Talk &amp;ldquo;What is RCU and How Does it Help the Linux Kernel Scale?&amp;quot;, Paul E. McKenney, Software Engineer at Meta Abstract:
RCU is used heavily as a replacement for reader-writer locking. But it is not a reader-writer lock. RCU is also used as a replacement for reference counting. But it is not a reference counter. RCU is used to provide type-safe memory. But it is not type-safe memory. RCU is used for many things, but it is none of those things.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/2024/home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/2024/home/</guid><description>VHPC 2024 - 19th Workshop on Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing The 19th Workshop on Virtualization in High­-Performance Cloud Computing (VHPC 2024) aims to bring together researchers and industrial practitioners facing the challenges posed by virtualization in HPC/Cloud scenarios in order to foster discussion, collaboration, mutual exchange of knowledge and experience, enabling research to ultimately provide novel solutions for virtualized computing systems of tomorrow.
The workshop will be held in conjunction with the International European Conference on Parallel and Distributed Computing (Euro-Par 2024), on Aug 27th, 2024, in Madrid, Spain.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/2024/program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/2024/program/</guid><description>VHPC 2024 Program Keynote: Towards Using Partitioned GPU Virtual Functions for Mixture of Experts Vignesh Chander, Member of Technical Staff, AMD
This talk provides an in-depth overview of the ROCm software ecosystem on MI300X platforms, with a focus on large-scale training and inference of Large Language Models. It will also introduce some new use cases that leverage the new Spatial Partitioning modes and Virtualization capabilities to accelerate these workloads. Additionally, we will discuss some of the challenges and tools available for profiling, tuning, and debugging these complex systems, empowering developers to optimize their workloads and unlock the full potential of MI300X.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/2024/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/2024/schedule/</guid><description>VHPC 2024 Schedule Notes pad: https://pad.nbfc.io/p/vhpc2024
For detailed information on the contributions, including full authorship, please, refer to the program page.
13:25-13:30 Welcome Message from the VHPC&amp;rsquo;24 Chairs
13:30-14:25 Keynote Talk &amp;amp; Paper Presentation (session chair: Tommaso Cucinotta)
13:30-14:25 Towards Using Partitioned GPU Virtual Functions for Mixture of Experts. Vignesh Chander (Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.) 14:25-15:00 Session 1 (session chair: Luca Abeni)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/jsa_si/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/jsa_si/</guid><description>Special Issue: Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing Journal of Systems Architecture (JSA) Elsevier a first quartile Scientific Journal Ranking/CiteScore ranked journal
Submission deadline: December 24th, 2023 (last extension for this Special Issue) This JSA Special Issue solicits original, high-quality submissions related to topics of interest for the VHPC series of workshops, i.e., virtualization across the entire software stack with a special focus on the intersection of HPC, Containerization/Virtualization and Cloud/Edge Computing.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/program/</guid><description>VHPC 2025 Program Tutorial: Writing a hypervisor from scratch, Seiha Nuta, Vercel, Inc. Accepted Paper Presentations Enabling RDMA and GPUs in Rootless Kubernetes for Accelerated HPC and AI Applications. Lisa Jolicoeur et al.
Performance Analysis of Container-in-VM Architectures: A Study on Hypervisor Isolation and Lightweight OS Integration. Manoj Patra et al.
WebAssembly and Unikernels: A Comparative Study for Serverless at the Edge. Enrico Fiasco et al.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/schedule/</guid><description>VHPC 2025 Schedule For detailed information on the contributions, including full authorship, please, refer to the program page.
09:00 - 09:50 Tutorial: Writing a hypervisor from scratch
Seiha Nuta 09:50 - 10:30 Paper: Enabling RDMA and GPUs in Rootless Kubernetes for Accelerated HPC and AI Applications
Lisa Jolicoeur et al. 10:30 - 11:00 Coffee Break
11:00 - 11:30 Paper: Performance Analysis of Container-in-VM Architectures: A Study on Hypervisor Isolation and Lightweight OS Integration</description></item><item><title>18th Workshop on Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing</title><link>https://vhpc.github.io/2023/home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/2023/home/</guid><description>The Workshop on Virtualization in High­-Performance Cloud Computing (VHPC) aims to bring together researchers and industrial practitioners facing the challenges posed by virtualization in HPC/Cloud scenarios in order to foster discussion, collaboration, mutual exchange of knowledge and experience, enabling research to ultimately provide novel solutions for virtualized computing systems of tomorrow.
News Aug 30th, 2023: VHPC&amp;rsquo;23 Proceedings now available on-line within the ISC 2023 Workshop Proceedings. Jun 15th, 2023: The CfP for the Elsevier JSA Special Issue on VHPC is on-line.</description></item><item><title>18th Workshop on Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing</title><link>https://vhpc.github.io/2023/jsa_si/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/2023/jsa_si/</guid><description>Special Issue: Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing Journal of Systems Architecture (JSA) Elsevier a first quartile Scientific Journal Ranking/CiteScore ranked journal
Submission deadline: December 24th, 2023 (last extension for this Special Issue) This JSA Special Issue solicits original, high-quality submissions related to topics of interest for the VHPC series of workshops, i.e., virtualization across the entire software stack with a special focus on the intersection of HPC, Containerization/Virtualization and Cloud/Edge Computing.</description></item><item><title>18th Workshop on Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing</title><link>https://vhpc.github.io/2023/program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/2023/program/</guid><description>VHPC 2023 Program For exact timing and schedule of the contributions, please, refer to the schedule page.
Keynote Talk &amp;ldquo;What is RCU and How Does it Help the Linux Kernel Scale?&amp;quot;, Paul E. McKenney, Software Engineer at Meta Accepted Paper Presentations Event-Driven End-to-End Testing For Containerized Applications. F. Nikolaidis, A. Chazapis, M. Marazakis, A. Bilas (FORTH, Hellas, and University of Crete, Greece) Performance losses with virtualization: Comparing bare metal to VMs and containers.</description></item><item><title>18th Workshop on Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing</title><link>https://vhpc.github.io/2023/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/2023/schedule/</guid><description>VHPC 2023 Schedule (tentative) 08:45-09:00 Welcome Message from the VHPC&amp;rsquo;23 Chairs
09:00-10:00 Keynote Talk
&amp;ldquo;What is RCU and How Does it Help the Linux Kernel Scale?&amp;quot;, Paul E. McKenney, Software Engineer at Meta 10:00-11:00 Paper Session 1
Event-Driven End-to-End Testing For Containerized Applications. F. Nikolaidis, A. Chazapis, M. Marazakis, A. Bilas (FORTH, Hellas, and University of Crete, Greece) Performance losses with virtualization: Comparing bare metal to VMs and containers.</description></item></channel></rss>