<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>17th Workshop on Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing</title><link>https://vhpc.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on 17th Workshop on Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vhpc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/program-details/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/program-details/</guid><description>VHPC 2022 Program Details (schedule to be defined soon)
Keynote Talks rtla: finding the sources of OS noise on LinuxDaniel Bristot De Oliveira, Senior Principal Software Engineer in the real-time kernel team at Red Hat. Currently, Real-time Linux is evaluated using a black-box approach. While this method provides an overview of the system, it fails to provide a root cause analysis for unexpected values. Developers have to use kernel trace features to debug these cases, requiring extensive knowledge about the system and fastidious tracing setup and breakdown.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/program/</guid><description>VHPC 2022 Tentative Program (schedule to be defined soon)
Keynote Talks &amp;ldquo;rtla: finding the sources of OS noise on Linux&amp;quot;, Daniel Bristot De Oliveira, Senior Principal Software Engineer in the real-time kernel team at Red Hat. Currently, Real-time Linux is evaluated using a black-box approach. While this method provides an overview of the system, it fails to provide a root cause analysis for unexpected values. Developers have to use kernel trace features to debug these cases, requiring extensive knowledge about the system and fastidious tracing setup and breakdown.</description></item></channel></rss>