<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>17th Workshop on Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing</title><link>https://vhpc.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on 17th Workshop on Virtualization in High-Performance Cloud Computing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vhpc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/program-details/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/program-details/</guid><description>VHPC 2022 Program Details Keynote Talks rtla: finding the sources of OS noise on Linux Speaker: Daniel Bristot De Oliveira, Senior Principal Software Engineer in the real-time kernel team at Red Hat.
Abstract: Currently, Real-time Linux is evaluated using a black-box approach. While this method provides an overview of the system, it fails to provide a root cause analysis for unexpected values. Developers have to use kernel trace features to debug these cases, requiring extensive knowledge about the system and fastidious tracing setup and breakdown.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/program/</guid><description>VHPC 2022 Tentative Program (schedule to be defined soon)
Keynote Talks rtla: finding the sources of OS noise on Linux, Daniel Bristot De Oliveira, Senior Principal Software Engineer in the real-time kernel team at Red Hat. DynamoDB: NoSQL database services for predictable HPC workloads, Akshat Vig, Principal Software Engineer at AWS and Amit Purohit, Director of Database Services at AWS. Accepted Paper Presentations eBPF-based Extensible Paravirtualization, Luigi Leonardi, Giuseppe Lettieri, Giacomo Pellicci (University of Pisa) Virtual Clusters: Isolated, Containerized HPC Environments in Kubernetes, George Zervas, Anthony Chazapis, Yannis Sfakianakis, Christos Kozanitis, Angelos Bilas (FORTH &amp;amp; University of Crete) On the use of Linux Real-Time Features for RAN Packet Processing in Cloud Environments, Luca Abeni, Tommaso Cucinotta, Balazs Pinczel, Peter Matray, Murali Srinivasan, Tobias Lindquist (Scuola Superiore Sant&amp;rsquo;Anna &amp;amp; Ericsson) Analyzing Unikernel Support for HPC: Experimental Study of OpenMP, Abdulrahman Azab (University of Oslo &amp;amp; Mansoura University) Accepted Lightning Talks ToroV, a kernel in user-space to deploy server-less applications, Matias Vara (Vates SAS) Keep an eye on your busy-waiting, Remo Andreoli (Scuola Superiore Sant&amp;rsquo;Anna) Unified workload deployment on heterogeneous HPC clusters, Anastassios Nanos, George Ntoutsos, Charalampos Mainas (Nubificus LTD) Invited Talks Mobility and Elasiticity in High Performace Cloud Computing, Eric Jul (University of Oslo) Platform-level resource orchestration and abstraction layers in continuum platforms: the challenge of heterogeneity, Massimo Coppola (ISTI, CNR) Scalable containers in HPC and the convergence toward HPC clouds, Azat Khuziyakhmetov (GWDG) Virtualisation Overhead Analyzed Using IO500, Julian Kunkel (GWDG) Enroot and Pyxis – Lightweight, Unprivileged Containers for Slurm Clusters, Luke Yeager (NVIDIA) MPI-based Graph Computing with Serverless Fault Tolerance in Clouds, Peng Lin and Lin Ma (ByteDance) State of Kubernetes in Container Orchestration for Scientific Computing, Michael Alexander (BOKU Vienna and OeAW, Austria) General Information The 17th Workshop on Virtualization in High­-Performance Cloud Computing (VHPC 2022) aims to bring together researchers and industrial practitioners facing the challenges posed by virtualization in HPC/Cloud scenarios in order to foster discussion, collaboration, mutual exchange of knowledge and experience, enabling research to ultimately provide novel solutions for virtualized computing systems of tomorrow.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vhpc.github.io/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vhpc.github.io/schedule/</guid><description>VHPC 2022 Tentative Program &amp;amp; Schedule Date: June 2nd, 2022
Location &amp;amp; Room: Congress Center Hamburg (CCH), Hall Y2 - 2nd Floor (refer to the ISC-HPC pages for details)
09:00-10:00 Keynote Talk #1
rtla: finding the sources of OS noise on Linux, Daniel Bristot De Oliveira, Senior Principal Software Engineer in the real-time kernel team at Red Hat 10:00-11:00 Virtualization &amp;amp; Unikernels
Virtual Clusters: Isolated, Containerized HPC Environments in Kubernetes, George Zervas, Anthony Chazapis, Yannis Sfakianakis, Christos Kozanitis, Angelos Bilas (FORTH &amp;amp; University of Crete) Analyzing Unikernel Support for HPC: Experimental Study of OpenMP, Abdulrahman Azab (University of Oslo &amp;amp; Mansoura University) 11:00-11:30 Coffee Break</description></item></channel></rss>